vinay vanteddu



vinay.vanteddu01@gmail.com



4694519964



https://www.vanteddu.com

Summary

I'm a Site Reliability Engineer with 2 years of experience and 2+ years of experience as a Full-stack developer with foundational Internet technology who undertakes complex assignments, exciting maintainable implementations, and delivers superior performance. I practice SRE & DevOps and apply strong technical, functional, and analytical skills and operate with a strong sense of urgency, and thrives in a fast-paced setting in order to solve business problems expediently.

Experience



Stratitude

Apr 2019 - Present (2 years 7 months +)

- System configuration is committed to a git repository and automated/orchestrated to the extent practical
- Defined SLIs and SLOs for multiple applications.
- Teaching SRE principles and the importance of adopting blame postmortems, error budgets, and monitoring
- Integrated different monitoring solutions such as Splunk, Honeycomb, Prometheus, Graphana, AWS cloud watch, etc
- Developed and implemented Runbooks. Implemented cloud services IAAS, PAAS, and SaaS and providing monitoring solutions.
- All changes are ticketed in the ticketing system (Jira) for assignment and tracking
- When revisiting older configurations/architectures, refactor using lessons learned
- All documents are detailed and easy to follow for operational efficiency and team scalability
- Modeled font-end/app web servers using Vagrant and Ansible with Nginx, Memcached, and Apache for public cloud hosting needs
- · Created a Secure Continuous Delivery system using Git and GPG encryption to ensure the integrity of developer commits prior to deployment
- Provided step-by-step documentation for the Secure Continuous Delivery system to promote developer adoption
- Extensive SELinux troubleshooting experience
- Setup and maintained Atlassian's tools: Jira, Confluence, and Crowd. Apache reverse-proxy to allow SSL cert sharing
- Troubleshoot complex network, POS, and systems issues



Student Internship

RosenbergLPA

Jan 2019 - Jun 2019 (6 months)

Constructed a language model to generate a Property Deed Document based on sample Deed Documents data.

worked on vector space technique represents each word in a language.

Derived meaningful insights and pattern identifications.

A model was built using python and Numpy.

Graduate Research Assistant

University of South Dakota

Aug 2018 - Jan 2019 (6 months)

Involved in the design and development of new features using AngularJS.

Created REST API using Express and Node.

Implemented global application search feature using Elastic Search and Kibana.

7 Full-stack Developer

Artists Affiliated Pvt Ltd

Oct 2016 - Nov 2017 (1 year 2 months)

Involved in the design and development of new features using AngularJS.

Worked on Restful APIs and Node JS

Designed and implemented the User Interface using JavaScript, HTML, XHTML, XML, CSS, JSP.

Used HTML, jQuery, and CSS for the frontend and MYSQL for the database.

Experience in software unit testing and efficiency at fact-finding, root cause analysis, and bug-fixing.

Education



SRM University

Bachelor's degree, Electrical and Electronics Engineering 2012 - 2016

👣 University of South Dakota

Master's degree, Computer Science

Skills

JavaScript • Microservices • React.js • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Ansible • Honeycomb • Splunk • Ansible • Docker Products • Kubernetes